Contact

margekaras@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/margekaras (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Leadership Quality Improvement Oncology Nursing

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

CITI Human Research

Quality Improvement

Chemotherapy and Biotherapy Provider

ACLS

CMSRN

Honors-Awards

Good Catch

Good Catch

Employee of the Year

Capstone Excellence Award

Biochemistry Exemplar Performance Award

Publications

Adressing the CLABSI: Dual nurse verification for dressing changes

Marge Karas MSN, RN, OCN, CMSRN

Clinical Medical Liaison representing GSK

Greater Milwaukee Area

Summary

Collaborate with Community Medical Experts and HCPs within the Gynecologic Oncology specialty.

Responsible for translating high-level scientific knowledge into presentations supporting clinical needs specific to Ovarian Cancer.

Oncology clinical leader and formal health policy advocate.

Providing better patient outcomes in oncology through the delivery of evidence-based care, empowerment of nurses, and a dedicated and educated care team. Providing clinical expertise at the state level for protocol development for the EHR platform. Development of oncology core nursing competencies and training.

Oncology Certified Nurse

Medical-Surgical Certified Nurse

CITI trained (learner group 3) to serve as principal investigator in

Oncology Nursing Society Health Policy Advocate
Southeastern Wisconsin Oncology Nursing Society (SWONS) Board-Government Relations

Wisconsin Cancer Council Member

Wisconsin Breast Cancer Coalition Education Chair

Oncology Nursing Society Congress Presenter- Research

Research Council Chair

human research

Journal Club Chair-Elect

Falls Committee Co-Chair

Abstract reviewer- Research Oncology Nursing Society Congress

Experience

Syneos Health Community Medical Liaison December 2019 - Present (7 months)

- Collaborate with Community Medical Experts and HCPs within the Gynecologic Oncology specialty
- Responsible for translating high-level scientific knowledge into presentations supporting clinical needs specific to Ovarian Cancer

Ascension

2 years 3 months

Clinical Nurse Specialist April 2019 - December 2019 (9 months)

Wisconsin

Acute care clinical nurse specialist, med-surg/ oncology focused, part of the state care transformation team. Focus on improving patient outcomes via evidence-based practice initiatives, nursing education, trend analysis, and innovative research throughout Ascension WI's 23 acute care hospitals.

Clinical Manager, Inpatient Oncology & Intermediate Care October 2017 - April 2019 (1 year 7 months)

All Saints Hospital, Racine, WI

Clinical nurse manager of the 20 bed inpatient oncology unit and 20 bed specialty intermediate care unit.

Froedtert Hospital
Staff Registered Nurse
March 2012 - January 2018 (5 years 11 months)

Level 4 nurse in Hematology, Oncology, & Palliative Care, Research Council Chair, Housewide Journal Club Chair, Mentor

Aurora Health Care Medical Assistant January 2005 - March 2012 (7 years 3 months) Greater Milwaukee Area

Cancer Care, Surgical procedures, orthopedic casting, & wound care

University of Utah Health Hospitals and Clinics CNA, Health Unit Coordinator, HIV Counselor June 2001 - December 2004 (3 years 7 months)

Greater Salt Lake City Area

Acute care oncology

Education

Western Governors University

Master of Nursing- MSN, Nursing Leadership & Management · (2016 - 2017)

Western Governors University

Bachelor of Science Nursing -BSN, Nursing · (2016 - 2017)

Bryant & Stratton College - Wauwatosa
Associate of Nursing -ADN, Nursing Education · (2013 - 2014)